<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>untagged on whatnowbrowncow</title>
    <link>https://whatnowbrowncow.github.io/tags/untagged/</link>
    <description>Recent content in untagged on whatnowbrowncow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 11:00:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://whatnowbrowncow.github.io/tags/untagged/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Snowflakes snowflakes everywhere, network automation in a brownfield world!</title>
      <link>https://whatnowbrowncow.github.io/posts/2022/02/snowflakes-snowflakes-everywhere-network-automation-in-a-brownfield-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 11:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whatnowbrowncow.github.io/posts/2022/02/snowflakes-snowflakes-everywhere-network-automation-in-a-brownfield-world/</guid>
      <description>I want to start this blog post by clearing something up; when you decide to start exploring network automation you&amp;rsquo;re essentially starting at the bottom of the mountain, therefore you&amp;rsquo;d be ill advised to try and plot a new path and get to the top on your own. You&amp;rsquo;re much better off taking the path well troden, following the examples of others and ultimately re-using people&amp;rsquo;s code and ideas.
Now that might sound like plagerism but it&amp;rsquo;s really not, as you get more involved in the coding community (community being the key word here) you come to realise that a lot of code is made up of little bits of other people&amp;rsquo;s code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The network developer&#39;s toolkit</title>
      <link>https://whatnowbrowncow.github.io/posts/2021/03/the-network-developers-toolkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 19:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whatnowbrowncow.github.io/posts/2021/03/the-network-developers-toolkit/</guid>
      <description>Following on from my first blog post about the changing world of network engineering I thought it would be a good idea to talk about some of the tools and technologies that will form your &amp;lsquo;go to&amp;rsquo; toolkit for network automation.
Just to be clear, this is not a comprehensive list of everything you need to know, nor is it an endorsement of any particular technology over another, this is simply a collection of tools that I use regularly as part of my automation development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The changing world of the network engineer....</title>
      <link>https://whatnowbrowncow.github.io/posts/2021/02/the-changing-world-of-the-network-engineer..../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 21:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whatnowbrowncow.github.io/posts/2021/02/the-changing-world-of-the-network-engineer..../</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s no getting away from it, the role of the modern network engineer is changing.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve been keeping even a cursory eye on recent developments within the networking community, you’ll have done well to avoid terms like NetDevOPs, Infrastructure as code, Network programability and Software Defined Networking.
Make no mistake, network automation is here and it’s here to stay.
Inevitably that realisation can be a little unsettling, it means change, potentially significant change, to an industry that’s remained comfortingly static for the past decade or three.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
