<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>untagged on whatnowbrowncow</title>
    <link>https://whatnowbrowncow.github.io/tags/untagged/</link>
    <description>Recent content in untagged on whatnowbrowncow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 22:10:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://whatnowbrowncow.github.io/tags/untagged/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The network developer&#39;s toolkit</title>
      <link>https://whatnowbrowncow.github.io/posts/2021/02/the-network-developers-toolkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 22:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whatnowbrowncow.github.io/posts/2021/02/the-network-developers-toolkit/</guid>
      <description>Following on from my first blog post about the changing world of network engineering I thought it would be a good idea to talk about some of the tools and technologies that will form your &amp;lsquo;go to&amp;rsquo; toolkit for network automation.
Just to be clear, this is not a comprehensive list of everything you need to know, nor is it an endorsement of any particular technology over another, this is simply a collection of tools that I use regularly as part of my automation development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The changing world of the network engineer....</title>
      <link>https://whatnowbrowncow.github.io/posts/2021/02/the-changing-world-of-the-network-engineer..../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 21:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whatnowbrowncow.github.io/posts/2021/02/the-changing-world-of-the-network-engineer..../</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s no getting away from it, the role of the modern network engineer is changing.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve been keeping even a cursory eye on recent developments within the networking community, you’ll have done well to avoid terms like NetDevOPs, Infrastructure as code, Network programability and Software Defined Networking.
Make no mistake, network automation is here and it’s here to stay.
Inevitably that realisation can be a little unsettling, it means change, potentially significant change, to an industry that’s remained comfortingly static for the past decade or three.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
